Now I know that the title
is clickbaity as shit, but ultimately,
there is a way
that you can make more money without doing
more work, and it's getting better at
making landing pages. A landing page
is like a brochure.
It's like a menu where you send people to
where they consider doing business with
you. And the majority of them,
unfortunately, are shit.
The reason I want to make this video
is so there's one resource in place I can
send
people every time someone says, "James,
why aren't I making sales?
I sent 300 people, no one bought." Yeah,
well, go watch this video because I'll
explain exactly why.
And for some of you watching this
thinking, oh, I know this
already,
Alex Hormozi says a lot of waffle,
but one thing he said that's legit the
other day is people need to be reminded
more than they need to be taught.
You might already know some of this stuff,
but you need to be reminded.
First things first,
I can never get behind sending people from
social media to a
landing page.
It's like first approaching someone at the
bar and saying, "Hey, do
you want to come suck my willy?" Because
if you were to do the process right and go
for loads of dinners and dates
and treat that person really well,
they might end
up really enjoying sucking your willy.
But if you say, "Suck my willy" too soon,
they go, "Whoa, wrong person." You didn't
do the steps necessary to get to the willy
sucking.
A landing page is not a website,
and so many of you try
and host your landing page
on your Wix or your Squarespace on a
website that's too multifaceted to do too
many different things,
and it ends up looking shit.
Leadpages and ClickFunnels,
all of these sites wouldn't be able to
charge the
premium of what they do of $49 US a month
unless they had a real,
tangible benefit to the amount of
bottom-line sales that you're making.
Another big consideration to make as well
is when people do land on these landing
pages,
we are not trying to force them to buy.
We're trying to coerce them.
If you're the manager of a restaurant
and someone's looking at your menu,
you don't
say, "Get inside. Go take
that seat over there."
You're like, "Hey, if you want to come in,
I'd love to have you here.
But again, I respect you
if you want to go somewhere else,
maybe check a few other
restaurants out.
It's also completely fine."
Which one of those two is going to
make you more likely to want to go into
that person's restaurant?
My biggest gripe is on websites, there
are far too many places for people to
click.
About Me, Services, Contact Us.
There needs to be one ultimate goal from
a landing page, and that is so
that someone goes from not doing business
with you
to start doing business with you.
And some people can sometimes confuse a
squeeze
page with a landing page.
A squeeze page has one objective
and one objective only,
that someone arrives on that
and gives you their contact information.
The landing page is
that someone lands on that page,
and they end up doing business
with you.
So to pay off the title of this about how
to make more money without
doing more work is
if you can improve the efficacy of your
landing page--
[power tool sound] I'm cursed at the
moment.
I don't know what I've done
or who I've annoyed,
but anytime I start recording
content,
someone has some type of power tool in the
neighborhood or the vicinity.
The reason that I love using landing pages
as much as anything else is the
analytics that we can get.
We can see the visitors,
and we can look at the
conversions,
and we could classify success as someone
clicking through to the
checkout. Although I know some people
are going to click through to the checkout
and maybe bounce,
let's just look at it like that.
But we can now identify.
If you're getting 1,000 people land on the
page and only one person's bought,
that's a conversion issue.
Maybe the structure, maybe the layout,
maybe the offer.
You might be tripping yourself up with
some of the things
that we're going to talk
about in a second, or ultimately,
you could be too expensive.
And a massive mistake that people make
is they think they get to dictate the
price.
"Well, I did a master's degree,
and I've got a BFE in
Kinesiology, so I should be getting $120 a
week." You don't determine what you charge
for an hour.
The demand for your services
is in charge of what you get an hour.
Because I don't care what qualifications
you've got, if no one wants to use your
services, the prices need to come down,
so it's easier to get people in because
you
want to be busy as a priority.
You'd rather have 30 clients
underpaying you than three clients paying
the going rate that you think you're
worth. And ultimately, again,
someone such as myself,
I charge a fortune, and I'm
one of the most underqualified people ever
because in some weird way, I'm not even
sure how,
I've created demand for my services.
Demand is the currency
that determines how much money we get.
So if loads of people landing,
no one's buying, conversion issue.
But if 10 people are landing
and one to two of them are buying,
we've got great
conversion, and the issue
is the bottleneck to that is traffic,
and if you're not
looking at the analytics,
it becomes very difficult to understand
when we have a
traffic issue and
when we have a conversion issue.
Now, one of the reasons as well
that a lot of people can leave a lot of
money on
the table is this.
We go through periods of being hot
and cold.
Some people arriving on your landing page
are hot. They are ready to go.
They're ready to buy.
They've just had an argument with their
ex, and they're going
to get the revenge body,
or they've just gone into their overdrive
and they're sick
of being single. Whatever it is.
Or they've just hurt their shoulder
getting up off
the sofa, and this
is the time they're going to get a physio
to help them mend
themselves.
If they land on their landing page
and you give them a cold outcome,
book in a sales call,
inquire for coaching.
People don't want a sales call.
They want to get going.
They want to start now. People that
are going to be your best clients
are usually
the most impatient. They're the ones
that will pay the most money.
The same way that if I buy something for
$10, if it's $12 to get it come a day
earlier, I'm paying it,
even though the thing only costs $10.
I want it tomorrow.
I want it right now. In fact,
the majority of the tech sat in front of
me, when I
order it online,
I can get it the next day
or within two to four hours,
and I can pay an Uber driver to come get
it.
"Babe,
I've just bought a new DJI Pocket Osmo 3."
"Oh, yeah?" "It's going to be
here in two hours,
so can you be by the door for
when it arrives?" Because I'm hot.
I wanted the camera, and now I've got it.
By booking in a sales call
or putting off the process till later,
you allow people
to cool down. They become more rational,
and ultimately, by the time you come
around to the call, they may want it less.
And I hate inquiry forms.
Inquire for coaching. You're not
that important.
It's not like I'm inquiring to see whether
or not I can book you for a nightlife
appearance in three weeks' time because
you've been on "Love Island." Just show
your prices and let people buy.
If you want to jump on a call
and chat with
them,
do it as part of your onboarding process.
"Hey, Steve, once you buy,
we're going to jump on a call for half
hour to get to
know each other. And just to let you know,
Steve, you still have a money-back
guarantee." If you have a money-back
guarantee,
you shouldn't have to need a sales
call. If you have a money-back guarantee,
you shouldn't need an inquiry form.
You should get the money from the person
so you can start doing what you're doing.
One of the best things
that you can do for your process,
for your sales, for your
funnel, is to put a VSL,
a video sales letter, or a video
that just sits
top and center of the page.
And it's just going to do
and say what everything does
on the page. Because imagine this.
I've said this a million times before.
Whenever I was single and dating,
a picture was never enough of a girl
because the
amount of girls that look good in
pictures, and I saw them in real life,
and I'm
like,
"You look nothing like you look like in
your pictures." If I could see a
video of them, I could build trust
and understand what they look like
and when they
move. And ultimately,
the same thing happens
when you watch a video of someone not
overly edited, not overly polished,
just off the cuff like this one.
I'm not reading any notes.
I'm just yarning.
You can get to understand how the person's
mind works.
You just sit there
and just say what it is, what they get,
why they need it, why to
trust you, how to pay. And have
that in the text and copy below in case
they're not
prepared to watch the video,
and then have a button to buy.
There are so many complexities.
With the inquiry form,
they might get bored and go,
"Oh, fuck this. I'll come back later,"
and they never come back.
With the booking in the sales call,
you either have loads of availability in
your
diary, so they think you're a shit
and not very good at your job,
or you have no
availability in your diary because you're
trying to do that thing where you go,
"Oh,
I'll just have two hours a day for sales
calls between 4:00 and
7:00,
so then they'll think I'm really busy."
But then they go through and go,
"Well, I'm at work from 4:00 till 7:00,
so fuck this guy.
I'll use someone else." Another thing,
men, you cannot design shit.
It's why your missus does the pillow
arrangements, and she makes the bed,
and she
puts the throws on it.
All of my friends
that as single men had a good-looking
bedroom and pillow arrangement on the bed,
I thought were gay because no straight
man knows what they're doing with color
palettes.
You can go to Adobe
and look at the color wheel
and look at what colors go with
what colors.
You dudes using a luminous green, red,
and black.
You're using colors of sex and violence.
Some of you guys are using pink
when you don't work with women,
and that's why a
lot of these lead pages,
landing pages ClickFunnels often have
color palettes
that are already designed and thought out.
So many of you, while doing videos,
aren't eye-level.
You're looking down at people. "Hey, guys,
welcome to my program." This camera is
on eye-level right now because then we're
looking to each other.
If I go down and look up to you,
it makes me look inferior.
If I go high and look down,
it looks like you're inferior.
The most people that
are personal trainers
or have been coaches before, you adjust
yourself to your client's eye level.
When they're down on the floor doing ab
crunches, you go down to match the eye
level so you're not looking down at them.
You need to do the same
when you're recording your own content.
And just remember,
if you're not getting many clients,
let's look at the landing
page.
If you're not getting enough traffic,
let's move to the segment above, which
is going to be email marketing.
I've done loads of videos on that before.
If your email list is stagnant and dry,
and you're not getting enough traffic from
that, you need to go to socials
and awareness and get more people to join
your
email list. There should be a trickle,
like a chocolate fondue fountain coming
down
all of the time, and
if there's ever a time
that your sales don't look the way they
want to, you need to analyze
and understand, "Where
is the bottleneck in my
process of the chocolate fondue?" Now,
one thing that's cropped up a lot recently
that I want to just die and go away
is commitment periods.
"Hey, guys,
it's $300 a month with a commitment period
of six months.
You must commit to me because I am a
coach, and I..." What are you
doing? You're looking desperate. I get it.
You want cash up front, so
if they're a bad client,
or they mess you around, you
don't—but stop it, because ultimately,
there is risk on either side here.
This is why we have the money-back
guarantee.
The person arriving on your site carries
all of the risk because they think
you're crap at what you do because the
majority of people that do what you do are
crap. Let's be honest.
By you taking the money-back guarantee,
you take that risk
from them, and you hold it yourself.
But what's the point of having a
money-back guarantee and doing
that with the risk
if you're going to have a commitment
period?
Again,
I've sometimes looked at Airbnbs to stay.
I've found real nice Airbnbs,
and I'm like, "We're going to stay here.
It's really expensive,
but I love the place." I'm already
imagining myself sleeping
in that Airbnb. Then I look.
Minimum two-night commitment. Fuck you.
I'm not staying. I'm not interested.
I'm going to a hotel.
You can fuck off.
I don't like being forced
and confined into things.
When I'm out and about,
I get my coffee in a takeaway cup because
I don't want to
feel that I have to be tied to the cafe.
If I want to get up and go for a walk,
I'm going for a walk. It's me and my son.
They know what you're doing.
You're just trying to get a grab of money
up front.
Do you know what? There
are a lot of business mentorships online a
bit like mine,
and all of the people
that have come to me really annoyed with
the one that they've
come from,
really unhappy with the level of the
service or whatever it is, all of
them have been tied into commitment
periods, where they're like, "Oh, James,
it's
been six months,
and I've still got to pay them." Still
having to be
contractually obligated to pay someone
when you are no longer emotionally
invested or interested in their product,
course, or service is probably one of the
worst things in the world.
It's one of the reasons
that I'm so pissed off with
Whoop. I had a Whoop band for a bit,
and then after six months, I was over it,
and
I canceled it, and they're like,
"12 months.
You're in for 12 months." Now I will never
say a good thing about Whoop.
Fuck you, Whoop. Fuck you, Whoop.
And these people just find their way to
Trustpilot and leave you neggy reviews.
Let's be honest.
If someone three months into your program
doesn't want to be in your program,
they're going to email you, and
if you're a dick about it,
they're going to say
they've got an eating disorder,
or they're struggling with mental health,
and
you're going to have to refund them
anyway.
So just piss off the commitment because
ultimately, get rid of the commitment.
Give a money-back guarantee.
Stop putting up barriers to entry because,
for some
people, they are ready to buy.
They're hot. They're on your page.
They're ready to go.
Then they see a six-month commitment,
and you just give them
that one bit of ammunition
that they needed not to buy.
Take the risk on yourself because then you
can get more clients.
And a certain percentage of them will fuck
you around, but ultimately, so many of
you moaning about so many elements of your
business, if you had more clients coming
through,
the majority of your problems go away.
You would much rather have a higher churn,
10 clients coming in, two going away,
versus just three coming in.
And for so many of you,
you charge monthly or
quarterly as another way of trying to get
the cash up front.
Just make it as easy as possible for
that person to join you
and start with you because not everyone
has $800 in
their bank account ready to go at any
given point.
For some people,
they can afford your services,
but what they can't afford to do is
to splash down three months of upfront
payment to a coach they've never used
before,
which would take their bank account
straight to the red.
Whereas if you were to say, "Hey, guys.
It's $400 a month, but
if you want to pay weekly,
if you want to pay quarterly,
however you want to pay,
I will accept because I want to reduce the
barrier to
entry for you to start." Because someone
might only, in their budgeted account,
have a couple hundred dollars to play
with,
and that's going out with their friends
for a few drinks, a few groceries. And
if you reduce your barrier to entry to
100 bucks a week, they go,
"I'm getting paid next week.
I'll spend $100 joining this program." So
many of you are making it so much harder
than necessary.
Instead of seeing your landing page as a
thing that serves you and
your business, make it as something
that serves them to eradicate any
insecurities,
to remove all the barriers to entry,
that makes them get to the end of the
video
thinking, "Wow, my day is worse
if I don't take up this person on what
they're
doing." I'm going to give you a link to my
landing page, which is a little bit of a
website, in the description,
and I'm actually then going to show you my
squeeze
page,
which is where I have the 30 days of
life-changing business information.
Take a look at those pages.
Understand the format.
Appreciate they have one function
and one function only. One is for emails.
One is to get people to buy my course.
Get your landing page right,
and everything is easier.
Good day